Register of the Herbert Hoover subject collection, 1895-2006
Hoover Institution Archives
- EDITORIAL ANALYSES, 1928-1933 (Box 296-312)
  - Philippines, King and Broussard resolutions for freeing Philippines; also Representative Knutson bill, Senator Bingham's resolution calling for investigation of development, Hawes-Cutting Bill, Secretary Hurley's letter to Senator Bingham, Hawley-Cummings Bill, Governor General Dwight Davis' statement, see also President-Philippine freedom., October 1929, October 1929; December 1929; February 1930; February 1930; May 1930; July 1930
  - Philippine Independence Bill, Hare Bill, House vote, April 1932.
  - Philippine Independence, passage of bill, President's veto January 13, 1933; and Congress' overriding of veto., January 1933
  - Post Office Department, Postmaster General Brown's recommendation for government-owned post office building lease.
  - Power, Attorney General's Opinion on Cumberland Falls Issue, August 1930.
  - Prohibition, decisions of Circuit Court of Appeals, Philadelphia, reversing lower court decision holding buyer of liquor equally guilty with seller; and decision by Judge Dawson of Kentucky supporting position of lower court., November 1929
  - Public Utilities, Power, discussion of reorganization of Federal Power Commission; government ownership; federal and state conflicts of jurisdiction; Maine referendum barring export of power; federal control of utility financing methods, etc., September 1929 to July 1930.
  - Power Commission, report based on decision in Appalachian Power Company case holding that Commission has jurisdiction over tributaries to navigable streams, applied to New River, West Virginia project., April 1931
  - Power Commission, Bonner-King-Russell dispute and Senate effort to reconsider nominations, reinstatement of King, January 1931.
  - Power Commission, Senate vs. George Otis Smith, see also District of Columbia-Supreme Court Decision in George Otis Smith case., April 1931
  - Prison, proposed federal prison reorganization, President's plans for extending probation; farms for narcotic victims, also President's plan to ask $5,000,000 Federal Penitentiary Fund, August 1929.
  - Prohibition, American Bar Association Referendum for Repeal.
  - Prohibition Bureau, transfer from Treasury to Justice, See also Mellon, Secretary., May 1930.
  - Prohibition, expose by former Prohibition Director Campbell of New York.
  - Prohibition, Literary Digest poll, from, March 1930 to July 1930.
  - Prohibition, Ontario and Nova Scotia referendum reversing dry stand, November 1929.
  - Prohibition, proposals for referendum on, January 1930.
  - Prohibition, proposals of Tuttle, New York, U.S. District Attorney, for local option; GOP state convention stand on.
  - Prohibition, transfer of Prohibition Unit to Justice Department under Williamson Bill, February 1930.
  - Prohibition, Prohibition Administrator, A.W.W. Woodcock statement of policy on home brew, September 1930.
  - Public Domain Bills, April 1932.
  - Public Lands Policy, report of Committee headed by James R. Garfield, favored turning public lands to state control., March 1931
  - Public Lands Policy, President's selection of committee to study policy; discussion of protecting sub-surface rights to Federal government; reoganization of Reclamation Service, etc., September 1929
  - President. (Box 303)
    - Administration's first six months.
    - Comparative positions on various issues.
    - Acceptance Speech.
    - American Legion Speech.
    - Annual Message to Congress., 1932
    - Annual Message to Congress., 1931
    - Annual Message to Congress., 1930
    - Annual Message to Congress., 1929
    - Appointments.
      - Beverly, James R., Governor of Puerto Rico, see "Grew and Beverly.", January 1932
      - Boyden, R.W., to the Hague, April 1930.
      - Brewster, S.M., U.S. District Attorney, Kansas, December 1929.
      - Brown, General Lytle, Chief of Engineers, U.S. Army, see Guggenheim., September 1929
      - Brown, Colonel Thad H., to Radio Commission, see Guggenheim., September 1929
      - Burnet, David, Commissioner of Internal Revenue, see Roosevelt, Nichols., August 1930
      - Butte, Dr. George C., Vice Governor, Philippines, see Smith, George Otis., December 1930
      - Cardozo, Benjamin, Justice, U.S. Supreme Court, February 1932.
      - Chapin, Roy H., Secretary of Commerce, August 3, 1932.
      - Clark, J. Reuben, Jr., Ambassador to Mexico, October 1930.
      - Crisp, Charles R., Tariff Commission, September 27, 1932.
      - Crosby, General H.B., Commissioner of District of Columbia, March 1930.
      - Dawes, General Charles G., to Reconstruction Finance Corporation, January 1932.
      - Dawes, General Charles G., to Disarmament Conference Delegation, December 1931.
      - Diekeme, G.J., Minister to Holland, see Garrett., September 1929
      - Doak, William N., Secretary of Labor, November 1930.
      - Eastman, J.B., to Interstate Commerce Commission, see Woods, see also Sackett, Hopkins, and Brewster., December 1929
      - Edge, Walter, Ambassador to France, July 1929.
      - Everson, General William G., Chief, Militia Bureau, U.S.A., see Brown., October 1929
      - Forbes, W. Cameron, Ambassador to Japan, see McNider., 1930
      - Fuller, Major General Benjamin H., Commandant, Marine Corps, see Roosevelt, Nichols., August 1930
      - Garfield, James R., Public Lands Commission, see Brown., September 1929
      - Garrett, John W., Ambassador to Italy, see Diekeme., July 1929
      - Gibson, Hugh M., to Disarmament Conference Delegation, see Disarmament Conference Delegates., December 1931
      - Grew, Joseph C., Ambassador to Japan, February 1932.
      - Guggenheim, Harry F., Ambassador to Cuba, see also Brown., September 1929
      - Hopkins, R.J., Federal Judge, Kansas, see Sackett, see also Eastman., October 1929
      - Jardine, William M., Minister to Egypt, see Roosevelt, Nichols., July 1930
      - Jones, R.M., to Interstate Commerce Commission, see Eastman, see also Sackett., December 1929
      - Laughlin, I.B., Ambassador to Spain, October 1929.
      - Lee, W.E., to Interstate Commerce Commission, see Sackett, see also Tate., January 1930
      - MacArthur, Major General Douglas, Chief of Staff, U.S.A., see Roosevelt, Nichols., July 1930
      - Mahaffie, Charles D., to Interstate Commerce Commission, see Roosevelt, Nichols., August 1930
      - McNab, J.R., see Garfield., October 1929
      - Meyer, Eugene, to Governor, Federal Reserve Board, September 1930.
      - McNider, Hanford, Minister to Canada, June 1930.
      - McNinch, Frank R., to Federal Power Commission, December 1930.
      - Mellon, Andrew W., Ambassador to Great Britain, February 1932.
      - Mills, Ogden R., Secretary of Treasury, see Mellon-Mills Appointments., February 1932
      - Morrow, E.P., U.S. Board of Mediation, 1930.
      - Munro, Dana G., Minister to Haiti, see Roosevelt, Nichols., July 1930
      - O'Brien, Robert Lincoln, Chairman, Tariff Commission, November 1931.
      - Pomerene, Atlee, Chairman, Reconstruction Finance Corporation, July 26, 1932.
      - Ratshesky, A.C., Minister to Czechoslovakia, see Sackett., January 1930
      - Reicheldefer, Luther H., District of Columbia Commissioner, see Crosby., March 1930
      - Reed, Judge, to Federal Land Bank, October 1929.
      - Roosevelt, Nicholas, Governor of Philippines, (withdrawn)., July 1930
      - Roosevelt, Nicholas, Minister to Hungary, August 1930.
      - Roosevelt, Colonel Theodore, Governor to Puerto Rico.
      - Roosevelt, Theodore, Governor to Philippines, January 1932.
      - Sackett, Frederick M., Ambassador to Germany, December 1929.
      - Sparks, Will M., Federal Judge, Indiana, November 1929.
      - Smith, George Otis, Federal Power Commission, December 1930.
      - Stockton, G.B., Minister to Austria, see Sackett., January 1930
      - Swanson, Senator C.A., Disarmament Conference Delegation, see Disarmament Conference Delegates., December 1931
      - Tate, H.M., Interstate Commerce Commission, February 1930.
      - Taylor, R.V., Interstate Commerce Commission, see Brewster., December 1929
      - Thatcher, Thomas D., Solicitor General, see Willys, see also Crosby., February 1930
      - Thompson, Sam H., Federal Farm Board, March 1931.
      - Watson, Judge A.L., Federal Judge, see Eastman, see Sackett., December 1929
      - Willys, John N., Ambassador to Poland, March 1930.
      - Winslow, Samuel E., U.S. Board of Mediation, see Smith, George Otis., December 1930
      - Wooley, Dr. Mary E., Disarmament Conference Delegation, December 1931.
      - Woods, J.P., Interstate Commerce Commission, see Brewster, see Disarmament Conference Delegates, see Crosby., December 1929
      - Youngquist, A.A., Assistant Attorney General, November 1929.
      - Judge Parker, appointment to Supreme Court.
      - Judge Roberts, appointment to Supreme Court.
    - Business Conference. (Box 304)
      - Statement on business conditions, October 1929.
      - Business conditions statement, April 15, 1932.
      - Business Rehabilitation Program, October 1931 to December 1931.
      - Business Conference, unemployment situation, 1929-1931. (Box 305)
      - Business Conference, August 25-26, 1932.
    - Cabinet salary reductions.
    - Caribbean trip, includes San Juan, Puerto Rico, speech and Virgin Islands statement.
    - Cleveland Speech, October 15, 1932.
    - Cleveland Speech, American Bankers Association., October 1930
    - Coinage Bill Veto, first bill vetoed.
    - Consolidation of Federal Bureaus Proposal, December 1931.
    - Coolidge article in Saturday Evening Post, September 10, 1932.
    - D.A.R. Address, April 1930.
    - Des Moines Speech, October 4, 1932.
    - Destroyer reduction proposal, September 1931.
    - Detroit Speech, October 22, 1932.
    - Detroit trip to address American Legion, for editorial comment on speech, see President, American Legion speech., September 1931
    - Disarmament Proposal, in instructions to delegates to Geneva Disarmament Conference., June 22, 1932
    - Drought expenditures, report on, May 1931.
    - Drought relief statement, February 3, 1931.
    - Economy, Appeal to Nation., May 6 (Box 306)
    - Economy Message, July 1930.
    - Economy Message to Cabinet.
    - Economy program, tax increase proposals, October 1931.
    - Economy program, statement on deficit, June 2, 1931.
    - Economy, Reorganization Message, May 1932.
    - Economy statement, April 24, 1931.
    - Economy statement, September 25, 1931.
    - Economy warning, October 14, 1931.
    - Economy warnings, April 1930.
    - Election result.
    - Farm Board intervention, June 1931.
    - Farmers' moratorium, September 27, 1932.
    - Federal building projects announcement, May 12, 1931.
    - Proposal to aid federal land banks.
    - Signing of Federal Power Commission Bill.
    - First year of administration.
    - Florida patronage statement, 1929.
    - Foreign debt statement, November 23, 1932.
    - Foreign Relations Message, 1932.
    - Foreign Relations Message, 1930.
    - Four-point relief program, June 1932.
    - Emergency relief proposals.
    - Emergency relief, $20,000,000 Compromise Bill.
    - German armament question and Disarmament Conference, September 20, 1932.
    - Gettysburg speech, May 30, 1930.
    - Glendale, California, radio speech on election results, November 12, 1932.
    - Handshaking moratorium, February 1932.
    - Home Loan Bills.
    - Home Loan Bank and Home Ownership Conference.
    - Home Loan Bank proposal, November 1931.
    - Home Loan Board appointments, August 6, 1932.
    - Conference on Home Ownership, comment previous to Conference., 1931
    - Conference on Home Ownership, 1931.
    - Address to Conference on Home Ownership, 1931.
    - Home Ownership Conference, 1930.
    - Home Ownership Conference and Home Ownership Legislation, 1932.
    - Hospitalization Bill for Civilians, veto of.
    - Howell, Senator, prohibition incident, challenging "loose talk" in Congress., 1929
    - "Hurry Up" special message to Congress, January 1932.
    - Indianapolis speech, to business men., 1931
    - Indianapolis, campaign speech, October 28, 1932.
    - Inland Waterways, request for appropriation, March 1932.
    - Inland Waterways Program, Louisville speech, 1929.
    - Interior Department economy drive, May 1931.
    - International Chamber of Commerce Address, May 1931.
    - Kelley charges in New York World against Secretary Wilbur and Interior Department, October 1930.
    - King's Mountain speech, October 1930.
    - Labor speech, October 1930.
    - Laval Conference.
    - Laval Joint Statement on Conference.
    - Law enforcement message, April 1930.
    - Special message on law reform, February 1932.
    - Lincoln Day address, 1931.
    - Lincoln Tomb Dedication speech, June 1931.
    - Loan to China for wheat sales.
    - Louvain Library incident, involving Architect Warren's attitude in matter of inscription.
    - Madison Square Garden speech, October 31, 1932.
    - Marion, O., speech at Harding Memorial, June 1931.
    - Mellon tax increase proposals, December 1931.
    - Methodist Ecumenical Conference address by radio, October 1931.
    - Eugene Meyer appointment to Federal Reserve Board.
    - Muscle Shoals statement, previous to veto message.
    - Muscle Shoals veto message, March 1931.
    - Moratorium action to relieve German economic situation, reports from, June 24 to August 18, 1931. (Box 307)
    - Naval budget statement, November 12, 1931.
    - Naval economy drive, May 1931.
    - Naval reduction proposals, October 1931.
    - Navy Day speech, October 1931.
    - Navy Day statement, October 1932.
    - Navy League attack, April 1932.
    - Navy League attack by William Gardiner, President's Committee investigation and report, 1931.
    - Newspaper statement on emergency program, December 11, 1931.
    - New Year's Proclamation announcing Naval Treaty in effect, January 1931.
    - New York Herald-Tribune Conference of Women, address by radio, September 29, 1932.
    - Nine-Point Emergency Program, statement., July 29, 1932
    - "No Special Session" statement, May 1931.
    - "No Tax Increase" statement, March 1931.
    - Nicaraguan nonintervention policy, April 1931.
    - Signing of Norris Anti-Injunction Bill, March 1932.
    - speeches, includes King's Mountain, Cleveland, Detroit speech to Legion and Labor speech., October 1930
    - Omnibus pension veto, April 1932.
    - Request for $150,000,000 relief fund.
    - Pan-American Commercial Congress speech, October 1931.
    - Pan-American Day address, April 1931.
    - Personnel Administration Counsel, April 1931.
    - Philippine Freedom Bill veto, January 13, 1933.
    - Philippine Independence statement, October 1931.
    - Police Chiefs' Conference speech, October 1931.
    - Post Office economy drive, postal deficit, May 1931.
    - Power Commission, statement on nominations, January 1931.
    - Power Commission nominations, stand on, February 1931.
    - Premier MacDonald Joint Statement, October 1929.
    - President and 71st Congress.
    - Racketeers, rejection of federal drive on, December 1930.
    - Railroad consolidation, December 1930.
    - Railroads, statement of condition of, March 1932.
    - Railway wages, appeal for delay in consideration of, September 1930.
    - Ransdell bill creating Public Health Institute.
    - Reconstruction Finance Corporation.
    - Red Cross address, April 1930.
    - Radio Relief Appeal, on behalf of Community Chests Drive., October 16, 1932
    - Relief Coordination Program.
    - Relief Legislation statement of, July 7, 1932.
    - Relief Drive statement, October 18, 1931.
    - Relief legislation, statement of on Wagner Bill., June 24, 1932
    - Relief proposals, controversy with Garner.
    - Criticism of Congress for blocking reorganization program, January 3, 1933. (Box 308)
    - Reorganization efforts, including five-day week proposals, flat-rate salary cut proposal, etc.; April 9th conference, proposal of President to accept $1 a year salary; Hines' proposal to restrict payments of disability compensation, etc., 1932.
    - "Surprise Message" to Congress and supplementary statement on economic cooperation, April 1932.
    - Reorganization program, statement and September 10 letter to executive government officers on budget., September 13, 1932
    - Reorganization proposal, March 1932.
    - Reorganization efforts and Congress' rejection of reorganization proposal, March 1932.
    - Special message on reorganization, February 1932.
    - Message on government reorganization, submitting executive orders for reorganization, consolidation, etc., December 9, 1932
    - Richmond address, Taxation, etc., April 1932
    - Robinson, Senator, relief proposals; includes comment on letter to engineers opposing bond issue proposal; President's statement on Garner's building program; etc.
    - Roosevelt conference, November 1932.
    - Roosevelt conference invitation, based on President's telegram, November 12, 1932.
    - Roosevelt telegram offering negotiation on St. Lawrence Treaty, and President's reply, July 10, 1932.
    - St. Louis speech, November 4, 1932.
    - Senate and President.
    - Address to Senate on budget, May 31, 1932.
    - Senate, Power Commission nominations controversy, January 1931.
    - Senate statement, October 1929.
    - Shipping Board reorganization proposal, April 1932.
    - Short sales of grain statement, July 1931.
    - Short sales, pressure against and prospects of Congressional inquiry, February 1932.
    - Research Committee on Social Trends announced, December 1929.
    - Letter to Senator Smoot re soldiers' bonus, February 1931.
    - Spanish war veterans' pension veto, June 1930.
    - Tariff Commission letter requesting study of effect of debased currencies on imports and tariff protection, October 24, 1932.
    - Veto of Democratic tariff measure, May 1932.
    - Tax bill, statement on signing of bill, June 1932.
    - Third year of administration.
    - "Treasury Raids" statement, December 1930.
    - Tuskegee speech, April 1931.
    - Unemployment Commission, selection of, August 1930.
    - Unemployment Conference.
    - Wagner Bill veto.
    - Valley Forge speech, May 1931.
    - Statement on tariff, and fight over flexible provision of Hawley-Smoot Bill as presented in House and Senate bills., September 1929
    - Tax increase proposals, December 29, 1931, to June 2, 1932. (Box 309)
    - Wage reductions, July 1931.
    - Wage statement, April 1931.
    - Wagner-Garner Relief Bill veto, July 11, 1932.
    - War debts, letter to Borah, July 13, 1932.
    - War debts, special message to Congress, December 19, 1932.
    - Washington's Birthday address, 1932.
    - Washington police, comment on third degree investigation, August 1931.
    - Welfare Conference address, September 15, 1932.
    - Western trip, proposed, May 1930.
    - Wickersham report, message transmitting preliminary report, January 1930.
    - Wickersham report, message on, January 1931.
    - Wilkerson, Judge, promotion of.
    - Women, address to, October 7, 1932.
    - World Court, statement announcing intention to submit protocols to present session, November 1930.
    - World War Pension Bill, statement forecasting, warning by President, Mellon and Hines, June 1930.
    - Yorktown speech, October 1931.
  - Radio Monopoly Suit, May 1930.
  - Reappportionment, demand for 1932 National Republican Convention Platform, May 1929.
  - Republican prohibition plank, June 1932.
  - Rockefeller, John D., Jr., letter favoring repeal of 18th Amendment, June 1932.
  - Roosevelt, Governor Franklin D.
    - Unemployment insurance plan presented at state Federation of Labor meeting, August 1930.
    - Appointment of St. Lawrence Development Commission, August 1930.
    - Utilities policy and miscellaneous, April 1930.
    - Veto of bill to investigate New York City government; prison program, states' rights speech, old-age pension fight, March 1930.
    - Action in telephone rate case, prison program, message to legislature and miscellaneous subjects, January 1930.
    - speech to state Democratic Committee of Illinois attacking administration., December 1929
    - Bonus attitude, September 1932.
    - Baltimore speech, October 25, 1932.
    - Bridgeport, Connecticut, speech, September 3, 1932.
    - Butte speech promising silver conference, September 19, 1932.
    - Columbus, Ohio, speech, August 20, 1932.
    - Foreign debt statement, November 23, 1932.
    - Statement on Far Eastern policy supporting Stimson policy.
    - Pittsburgh speech, October 19, 1932.
    - Portland, Oregon, speech on power, September 21, 1932.
    - Prohibition statement in letter to Senator Wagner, September 9, 1930.
    - Radio address on 1932 Democratic Platform, July 30, 1930.
    - Radio "Forgotten Man" speech, April 7, 1932.
    - Radio speech on relief, Albany, October 13, 1932.
    - St. Paul, Minnesota, Jefferson Day Dinner, April 18, 1932.
    - Sales tax pronouncement, January 1933.
    - Salt Lake City speech on railroads, September 17, 1932.
    - Seagirt, New Jersey, speech on prohibition, August 27, 1932.
    - Seattle tariff speech, September 20, 1932.
    - Sioux City, Iowa, speech on farm relief, September 29, 1932.
    - Topeka, Kansas, farm relief speech, September 14, 1932.
  - Roosevelt, Nicholas.
    - Appointment as Governor General of Philippines and withdrawal of name after Filipinos had made demonstrations because of book he had written on capacity of Filipinos to govern themselves.
    - Appointment as Minister to Hungary, September 1930.
  - Round-robin letter of prominent men to Congress to speed up work, May 1932.
  - Rubio, President-elect of Mexico, visit to U.S., December 1930.
  - Russia, recognition of.
    - Secretary Stimson's study of recognition, March 1931.
    - Reply to Stimson note, rebuke to U.S.
    - Trade embargo, July 1930.
  - Russo-Chinese situation, Kellogg Pact, etc., July 1929.
  - Sackett-Insull incident, speech of Sackett in Berlin, June 1930. (Box 310)
  - St. Lawrence Power Project, New York State action for power commission., January 1930
  - St. Lawrence Waterway negotiations, Stimson-Herridge negotiations, selection of Senator J.H. Allen as special advisor, President's acceptance of Canadian suggestion for direct negotiation of treaty, October 1931.
  - St. Lawrence Waterway Treaty signing, announcement by President., July 13, 1932
  - Sales tax, House Ways and Means Committee report, March 7, 1932.
  - Shearer case, lobbying at Disarmament Conference; Shearer's suit against munition makers; President's denunciation, etc., September 1929.
  - Sheppard, Senator, bill to make buyer of liquor equally guilty with seller, October 1929.
  - Short selling of stocks, based on Stock Exchange report and on Capper, resolution for investigation, Watson's demand for investigation, etc., October 1929.
  - Sinclair, Harry, oil case, conviction and sentence, August 1929.
  - Smith, Alfred E.
    - Editorials in New Outlook magazine, initial number after Smith becomes editor, October 1932.
    - Jefferson Day speech, Washington, D.C., and denunciation of demagogues, April 1932.
    - Radio speech, on sales tax, government reorganization, veterans' relief, etc., May 16, 1932
    - Saturday Evening Post article on Soldiers' Bonus, September 1932.
    - His appointment, with Calvin Coolidge and Julius Rosenwald, to administer charitable bequest of Conrad Hubert, October 1929.
  - Soldiers' Bonus.
  - South American governments, State Department recognition policy, September 1930.
  - State Department, appropriations attacked as too small, November 1929.
  - Steagall Bank Guaranty Bill, May 1932.
  - Steel merger, court decision, December 1930.
  - Stimson, Secretary of State.
    - European trip, June 1931.